<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<html
	xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:wi="http://www.witbd.org/xmlns/sitebuilder/template" xmlns:st="http://www.witbd.org/xmlns/text/structure" xmlns:te="http://www.witbd.org/xmlns/text/basic/" xmlns:bib="http://www.witbd.org/xmlns/biblio/" xmlns:ch="http://xmlchar.sf.net/ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" >
<head>
	<title>Friends of the Creative Domain - Home Page</title>
	<wi:Metadata>
		<rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
			<rdf:Description rdf:about="">
				<dc:title>Friends of the Creative Domain - Home Page</dc:title>
				<dc:creator>Rufus Pollock</dc:creator>
				<dct:created>2004-07-05</dct:created>
				<dct:modified></dct:modified>
			</rdf:Description>
		</rdf:RDF>
	</wi:Metadata>
</head>

<body>
	<h1>
		Friends of the Creative Domain
	</h1>
	
	<st:TableOfContents />
	
	<st:Section>
		<h2>
			The Wiki
		</h2>
		<p>
			Friends of the Creative Domain primarily uses a <a href="wiki/">public wiki</a> for managing information. Go there if you are looking to contribute or to find information on FCD activities.
		</p>
	</st:Section>
	
	<st:Section>
		<h2>
			Contacting FCD
		</h2>
		<p>
			If you want more information please contact Rufus Pollock (email: fcd-info [at] okfn.org, phone: 07795 176 976).
		</p>
	</st:Section>
	
	<st:Section>
		<h2>
			About Friends of the Creative Domain
		</h2>
		<p>
			Friends of the Creative Domain was formed in mid 2004. Primarily created to encourage and support the BBC's efforts to make an open <a href="wiki/CreativeArchive">Creative Archive</a>. It brought together groups who have a stake in the archive such as artists, archivists, academics, educators, and of course the license paying general public.
		</p>
		<p>
			Since then it has retained its structure as a open community while the focus has evolved into a more general promotion of the public domain and of the creative commons.
		</p>
		<p>
			For more information about the organization see the <a href="about.html">about</a> page
		</p>
	</st:Section>
	
	<st:Section>
		<h2>How can I get involved?</h2>
		<p>
			There are various things you can do to participate:
		</p>
		<ul>
			<li>
				Contribute to the <a href="wiki/">wiki</a>
			</li>
			<li>
				<a href="making_your_views_known.html">Make your views known about the Creative Archive</a> or about <a href="wiki/PublicDomainElvis">music copyright extensions</a>. For example you could write to your MP. This is extremely valuable way of demonstrating support or concern about an issue.
			</li>
			<li>
				Join the creative-friends mailing list for discussion of this project, which you
				can sign up to <a href="http://lists.essential.org/mailman/listinfo/creative-friends">here</a>.
			</li>
			<li>
				Tell others about Friends of the Creative Domain and the issues it promotes such as Creative Commons and the Creative Archive.
			</li>
		</ul>
	</st:Section>
	
</body>
</html>