<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<html
	xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:wi="http://www.witbd.org/xmlns/sitebuilder/template" xmlns:st="http://www.witbd.org/xmlns/text/structure" xmlns:te="http://www.witbd.org/xmlns/text/basic/" xmlns:bib="http://www.witbd.org/xmlns/biblio/" xmlns:ch="http://xmlchar.sf.net/ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" >
<head>
	<title>Making Your Views Known</title>
	<wi:Metadata>
		<rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/">
			<rdf:Description rdf:about="">
				<dc:title>Making Your Views Known</dc:title>
				<dc:creator>Rufus Pollock</dc:creator>
				<dct:created>2004-07-05</dct:created>
				<dct:modified></dct:modified>
			</rdf:Description>
		</rdf:RDF>
	</wi:Metadata>
</head>

<body>
	<h1>Making Your Views Known</h1>
	<p>
		There are various things you can do:
	</p>
	<ul>
		<li>
			<a href="#write_mp">Write to your MP and DCMS</a>
		</li>
		<li>
			Subscribe to the <a href="http://lists.essential.org/mailman/listinfo/creative-friends">creative-friends mailing list</a>
		</li>
	</ul>
	
	<h2>
		<a name="write_mp">
			Writing to Your MP or DCMS
		</a>
	</h2>
	<p>
		To write to your MP we recommend you use <a href="http://www.faxyourmp.com">http://www.faxyourmp.com</a>.	If you have or are going to write it would be great if you <a href="contact.shtml">let us know</a> - this allows us to track how many people have written and to whom. We have also provided below a list of 'talking points' to assist in the drafting of a letter.
	</p>
	<p>
		To write to DCMS address your comments to:
<pre>  Matthew Hill
  Programme Manager, BBC Charter Review
  Broadcasting Policy Division
  Department for Culture, Media and Sport
  2-4 Cockspur Street
  London SW1Y 5DH
  UNITED KINGDOM
</pre>
	</p>
	
	<h3>
		Talking Points
	</h3>
	<p>
		Below are some of the things you might write to your MP. We haven't provided a form letter as they tend to be ignored or have significantly less impact (see <a href="http://www.faxyourmp.com/q_a.php3#formletters">here</a> for why). Drafting your own letter, even if is only to flesh out the points below, will result in your efforts having a far greater effect. At the same time if you would like any assistance or comments please <a href="contact.shtml">contact us</a>.
	</p>
	<ul>
		<li>
			Indicate that you are in their district.
		</li>
		<li>
			Note that you are a TV license-payer.
		</li>
		<li>
			Explain why this is an important issue to you, and how you would use the Creative Archive.
		</li>
	</ul>
	<ul>
		<li>
			Urge them to support language in the new charter that would ensure a
			robust Creative Archive, and to express this support to the charter
			renewal committee. Good charter language would protect the BBC's
			ambitions for an archive which:
			<ul>
				<li>
					Draws from all areas of the BBC's broadcasting from news to sport.
				</li>
				<li>
					Is available without "digital rights management" or other
					technology locks that will keep Britons from creatively re-using
					the BBC's offerings.
				</li>
				<li>
					Provides material licensed under conditions that do not
					restrict any licence-payer from accessing, storing, modifying or
					sharing archive material for non-commercial use.
				</li>
				<li>
					Provides material in its entirety for non-commercial use and
					not only in excerpted form.
				</li>
				<li>
					Includes material that the BBC already owns the rights in at
					its launch or as soon after its launch as is possible, with
					other material to follow as soon as rights are cleared.
				</li>
				<li>
					Benefits from future licensing agreements with independent
					producers that allow the BBC to make the works freely available
					for non-commercial use.
				</li>
			</ul>
		</li>
	</ul>
</body>

</html>